export const ch1 = [
  {
    mcq: [
      {
        numb: 1,
        question: "The biology is a __ word.",
        options: ["Latin", "Greek", "Scientific", "British"],
        answer: "Greek",
      },
      {
        numb: 2,
        question: "Biology derived from__.",
        options: [
          "Two Greek words",
          "Three Greek words",
          "Four Greek words",
          "One Greek word",
        ],
        answer: "Two Greek words",
      },
      {
        numb: 3,
        question: "The major divisios of biology are__.",
        options: ["Two", "Three", "Four", "Five"],
        answer: "Three",
      },
      {
        numb: 4,
        question: "The study of Animal is called__.",
        options: ["Zoology", "Botany", "Mircobiolog", "Biology"],
        answer: "Zoology",
      },
      {
        numb: 5,
        question: "The study of plants is call__.",
        options: ["Zoology", "Biology", "Microbiology", "Botany"],
        answer: "Botany",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    mcq: [
      {
        numb: 6,
        question: "The study of micro organisms is called___.",
        options: ["Zoology", "Biology", "Mircobiology", "Morphology"],
        answer: "Mircobiology",
      },
      {
        numb: 7,
        question: "The study of molecules of life is called__.",
        options: ["Biology", "Zoology", "Botany", "Molecular biology"],
        answer: "Molecular biology",
      },
      {
        numb: 8,
        question: "The study of internal structures is called__. ",
        options: ["Histology", "Anatomy", "Cell biology", "Biology"],
        answer: "Anatomy",
      },

      {
        numb: 9,
        question: "The microscopic study of tissues is called__ ",
        options: ["Cell biology", "Anatomy", "Zoology", "Histology"],
        answer: "Histology",
      },
      {
        numb: 10,
        question:
          "The study of the structures and functions of cells and cell organelles is called__",
        options: ["Biology", "Anatomy", "Histology", "Cell biology"],
        answer: "Cell biology",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    mcq: [
      {
        numb: 11,
        question: "The study of parsites is called__",
        options: ["Parastology", "Anatomy", "Botany", "Taxonomy"],
        answer: "Parastology",
      },
      {
        numb: 12,
        question: "The study of immune system is called__",
        options: ["Embryology", "Genetics", "socio biolog", "immunology"],
        answer: "immunology",
      },
      {
        numb: 13,
        question: "The study of insects is called__",
        options: ["Anatomy", "Biology", "Entomology", "Parastology"],
        answer: "Entomology",
      },
      {
        numb: 14,
        question:
          "The study of drugs and their effects on the system of human body is called__",
        options: ["Pharmacology", "Zoology", "Taxonomy", "Socio biology"],
        answer: "Pharmacology",
      },
      {
        numb: 15,
        question: "Jabir Bin Hayan was born in___",
        options: ["Iran ", "Iraq", "Itely", "Brazil"],
        answer: "Iran",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    mcq: [
      {
        numb: 16,
        question: "How many Bio elements are?",
        options: ["18", "16", "26", "92"],
        answer: "16",
      },
      {
        numb: 17,
        question: "Which of the followings is Mircomolecule?",
        options: ["Water", "Glucose", "A and B", "None of these"],
        answer: "A and B",
      },
      {
        numb: 18,
        question: "Which of the followings is Macromolecules?",
        options: ["Proteins", "Lipids", "A and B", "None of these"],
        answer: "A and B",
      },
      {
        numb: 19,
        question: "Prokaryotes have __?",
        options: ["Single cell", "Doubl cells", "Many cells", "None of these"],
        answer: "Single cell",
      },
      {
        numb: 20,
        question: "Epidermal tissues are examples of__",
        options: ["Animals", "Plants", "A and B", "None of these"],
        answer: "Plants",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    mcq: [
      {
        numb: 21,
        question: "Animals tissues are__",
        options: [
          "Nervous tissues",
          "Muscular tissus",
          "A and B",
          "Epidermal tissues",
        ],
        answer: "A and B",
      },
      {
        numb: 22,
        question: "The area of the environment in which organsim lives is called__.",
        options: [
          "Habitats",
          "community Level",
          "Biosphere Level",
          "Environment",
        ],
        answer: "Habitats",
      },
      {
        numb: 23,
        question: "Only one cell makes the life of an organism are called__",
        options: ["Multicellular", "Unicellular", "A and B", "None of these"],
        answer: "Unicellular",
      },
      {
        numb: 24,
        question: "The Scientific name of Mustard plant is _",
        options: [
          "Brassica campestris",
          "Rana tigrina",
          "Rose Indica",
          "None of these",
        ],
        answer: "Brassica campestris",
      },
      {
        numb: 25,
        question: "The scientific name of Frog is__",
        options: [
          "Brassica campestris",
          "Rana tigrina",
          "Rose indica",
          "None of these",
        ],
        answer: "Rana tigrina",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    mcq: [
      {
        numb: 26,
        question:
          "Members of the same species living in the same place at the same time make a__.",
        options: ["Habitat", "Biosphere", "community", "Population"],
        answer: "Population",
      },
      {
        numb: 27,
        question:
          "Which of these major biolelements is in the highest percentage in protoplasm",
        options: ["Carbon", "Hydrogen", "Oxygen", "Nitrogen"],
        answer: "Oxygen",
      },
      {
        numb: 28,
        question: "All the organisms have been divided into__major groups.",
        options: ["Three", "Six", "Five", "Four"],
        answer: "Five",
      },
      {
        numb: 29,
        question: "What is True about Volvox?",
        options: [
          "Unicellular Prokaryotes",
          "Multicellular Prokaryotes",
          "Colonial eukaryote",
          "Multicellular eukaryote",
        ],
        answer: "Colonial eukaryote",
      },
      {
        numb: 30,
        question:
          "Similar cells organized into groups and performing same function,are known as:",
        options: [" Organalle", "Tissue", "Organ", "Organ system"],
        answer: "Tissue",
      },
    ],
  },
];
export const ch1mcqs = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "The biology is a __ word.",
    options: ["Latin", "Greek", "Scientific", "British"],
    answer: "Greek",
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Biology derived from__.",
    options: [
      "Two Greek words",
      "Three Greek words",
      "Four Greek words",
      "One Greek word",
    ],
    answer: "Two Greek words",
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "The major divisios of biology are__.",
    options: ["Two", "Three", "Four", "Five"],
    answer: "Three",
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "The study of Animal is called__.",
    options: ["Zoology", "Botany", "Mircobiolog", "Biology"],
    answer: "Zoology",
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "The study of plants is call__.",
    options: ["Zoology", "Biology", "Microbiology", "Botany"],
    answer: "Botany",
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "The study of micro organisms is called___.",
    options: ["Zoology", "Biology", "Mircobiology", "Morphology"],
    answer: "Mircobiology",
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "The study of molecules of life is called__.",
    options: ["Biology", "Zoology", "Botany", "Molecular biology"],
    answer: "Molecular biology",
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "The study of internal structures is called__. ",
    options: ["Histology", "Anatomy", "Cell biology", "Biology"],
    answer: "Anatomy",
  },

  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "The microscopic study of tissues is called__ ",
    options: ["Cell biology", "Anatomy", "Zoology", "Histology"],
    answer: "Histology",
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question:
      "The study of the structures and functions of cells and cell organelles is called__",
    options: ["Biology", "Anatomy", "Histology", "Cell biology"],
    answer: "Cell biology",
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "The study of parsites is called__",
    options: ["Parastology", "Anatomy", "Botany", "Taxonomy"],
    answer: "Parastology",
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "The study of immune system is called__",
    options: ["Embryology", "Genetics", "socio biolog", "immunology"],
    answer: "immunology",
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "The study of insects is called__",
    options: ["Anatomy", "Biology", "Entomology", "Parastology"],
    answer: "Entomology",
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question:
      "The study of drugs and their effects on the system of human body is called__",
    options: ["Pharmacology", "Zoology", "Taxonomy", "Socio biology"],
    answer: "Pharmacology",
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Jabir Bin Hayan was born in___",
    options: ["Iran ", "Iraq", "Itely", "Brazil"],
    answer: "Iran",
  },
  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "How many Bio elements are?",
    options: ["18", "16", "26", "92"],
    answer: "16",
  },
  {
    numb: 17,
    question: "Which of the followings is Mircomolecule?",
    options: ["Water", "Glucose", "A and B", "None of these"],
    answer: "A and B",
  },
  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "Which of the followings is Macromolecules?",
    options: ["Proteins", "Lipids", "A and B", "None of these"],
    answer: "A and B",
  },
  {
    numb: 19,
    question: "Prokaryotes have __?",
    options: ["Single cell", "Doubl cells", "Many cells", "None of these"],
    answer: "Single cell",
  },
  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "Epidermal tissues are examples of__",
    options: ["Animals", "Plants", "A and B", "None of these"],
    answer: "Plants",
  },
  {
    numb: 21,
    question: "Animals tissues are__",
    options: [
      "Nervous tissues",
      "Muscular tissus",
      "A and B",
      "Epidermal tissues",
    ],
    answer: "A and B",
  },
  {
    numb: 22,
    question: "The area of the environment in which organsim lives is called__.",
    options: [
      "Habitats",
      "community Level",
      "Biosphere Level",
      "Environment",
    ],
    answer: "Habitats",
  },
  {
    numb: 23,
    question: "Only one cell makes the life of an organism are called__",
    options: ["Multicellular", "Unicellular", "A and B", "None of these"],
    answer: "Unicellular",
  },
  {
    numb: 24,
    question: "The Scientific name of Mustard plant is _",
    options: [
      "Brassica campestris",
      "Rana tigrina",
      "Rose Indica",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Brassica campestris",
  },
  {
    numb: 25,
    question: "The scientific name of Frog is__",
    options: [
      "Brassica campestris",
      "Rana tigrina",
      "Rose indica",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Rana tigrina",
  },
  {
    numb: 26,
    question:
      "Members of the same species living in the same place at the same time make a__.",
    options: ["Habitat", "Biosphere", "community", "Population"],
    answer: "Population",
  },
  {
    numb: 27,
    question:
      "Which of these major biolelements is in the highest percentage in protoplasm",
    options: ["Carbon", "Hydrogen", "Oxygen", "Nitrogen"],
    answer: "Oxygen",
  },
  {
    numb: 28,
    question: "All the organisms have been divided into__major groups.",
    options: ["Three", "Six", "Five", "Four"],
    answer: "Five",
  },
  {
    numb: 29,
    question: "What is True about Volvox?",
    options: [
      "Unicellular Prokaryotes",
      "Multicellular Prokaryotes",
      "Colonial eukaryote",
      "Multicellular eukaryote",
    ],
    answer: "Colonial eukaryote",
  },
  {
    numb: 30,
    question:
      "Similar cells organized into groups and performing same function,are known as:",
    options: [" Organalle", "Tissue", "Organ", "Organ system"],
    answer: "Tissue",
  },
]

export const ch2 = [
  {
    mcq: [
      {
        numb: 1,
        question:
          "__is the systemized knowledge derived from observations and experiments.",
        options: ["Biology", "Zoology", "Science", "Botany"],
        answer: "Science",
      },
      {
        numb: 2,
        question: "Galileo did his experiment in__.",
        options: ["1550s", "1590s", "1790s", "1593s"],
        answer: "1590s",
      },
      {
        numb: 3,
        question: "A liter of water is heavier than a liter of ethanol, it is__observation.",
        options: [
          "Qualitative observations",
          "Quantitative observations",
          "A and B",
          "None of these",
        ],
        answer: "Qualitative observations",
      },
      {
        numb: 4,
        question: "The freezing point of water is 0°C and boiling point is__",
        options: ["100°C", "80°C", "50°C", "45°C"],
        answer: "100°C",
      },
      {
        numb: 5,
        question: "The Italian words Mala means bad and Aria means__",
        options: ["Bad", "Air", "Water", "None of these"],
        answer: "Air",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    mcq: [
      {
        numb: 6,
        question:
          "The bark of a tree known as__was very suitable for curing fevers.",
        options: ["quina-quina", "cinchona", "Rose", "quinine"],
        answer: "quina-quina",
      },
      {
        numb: 7,
        question: " Plasmodium is the cause of__ ",
        options: ["Puenomia", "Dihrria", "Malaria", "None of these"],
        answer: "Malaria",
      },
      {
        numb: 8,
        question:
          "The hypotheses that stand the test of time (often tested and never rejected),are called__.",
        options: ["Theories", "hypotheses", "law", "None of these"],
        answer: "Theories",
      },
      {
        numb: 9,
        question: "Ronal Ross performed his experiments in__.",
        options: ["1880", "1888", "1855", "1853"],
        answer: "1880",
      },
      {
        numb: 10,
        question: "In sparrows malaria is spread by__.",
        options: [
          "Culex mosquito",
          "Marshy ares",
          "virus",
          "Anopheles mosquito",
        ],
        answer: "culex mosquito",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    mcq: [
      {
        numb: 11,
        question: "The malaria is spread in birds by__.",
        options: ["Anopheles", "Aedes", "culex", "Dengue"],
        answer: "Aedes",
      },
      {
        numb: 12,
        question: "Biological method comprises of___steps.",
        options: ["5", "7", "6", "8"],
        answer: "6",
      },
      {
        numb: 13,
        question: "A litre of water weighs__.",
        options: ["1000g", "989g", "780g", "879g"],
        answer: "1000g",
      },
      {
        numb: 14,
        question:
          "Female mosquitoes need the blood of__for the maturations of their eggs.",
        options: ["Mammals", "Birds", "A and B", "Reptiles"],
        answer: "A and B",
      },
      {
        numb: 15,
        question: "The most basic step of biological method is__.",
        options: [
          "observations ",
          "experimentation",
          "Deductions",
          "hypotheses",
        ],
        answer: "experimentation",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    mcq: [
      {
        numb: 16,
        question: "Cinchona bark contains__.",
        options: ["quinine", "quina-quina", "basoquine", "resochine"],
        answer: "quinine",
      },
      {
        numb: 17,
        question: "The number of organisms on Earth is almost__.",
        options: ["Ten thousand", "Two lac", "20 lac", "one crore"],
        answer: "one crore",
      },
      {
        numb: 18,
        question: 'Plasmodium is the cause of malaria. This statement is a__.',
        options: ["hypotheses", "Deductions", "Theory", "Law"],
        answer: "Law",
      },
      {
        numb: 19,
        question: "Man always remained a__.",
        options: ["biologist", "chemist", "geologist", "scientist"],
        answer: "biologist",
      },
      {
        numb: 20,
        question: "Which of the followings is an effective drug for treating Malaria?",
        options: ["Disprein", "Actified", "quinine", "Theragram"],
        answer: "quinine",
      },
    ],
  },
];
export const ch2mcqs = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question:
      "__is the systemized knowledge derived from observations and experiments.",
    options: ["Biology", "Zoology", "Science", "Botany"],
    answer: "Science",
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Galileo did his experiment in__.",
    options: ["1550s", "1590s", "1790s", "1593s"],
    answer: "1590s",
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "A liter of water is heavier than a liter of ethanol, it is__observation.",
    options: [
      "Qualitative observations",
      "Quantitative observations",
      "A and B",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Qualitative observations",
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "The freezing point of water is 0°C and boiling point is__",
    options: ["100°C", "80°C", "50°C", "45°C"],
    answer: "100°C",
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "The Italian words Mala means bad and Aria means__",
    options: ["Bad", "Air", "Water", "None of these"],
    answer: "Air",
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question:
      "The bark of a tree known as__was very suitable for curing fevers.",
    options: ["quina-quina", "cinchona", "Rose", "quinine"],
    answer: "quina-quina",
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: " Plasmodium is the cause of__ ",
    options: ["Puenomia", "Dihrria", "Malaria", "None of these"],
    answer: "Malaria",
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question:
      "The hypotheses that stand the test of time (often tested and never rejected),are called__.",
    options: ["Theories", "hypotheses", "law", "None of these"],
    answer: "Theories",
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Ronal Ross performed his experiments in__.",
    options: ["1880", "1888", "1855", "1853"],
    answer: "1880",
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "In sparrows malaria is spread by__.",
    options: [
      "Culex mosquito",
      "Marshy ares",
      "virus",
      "Anopheles mosquito",
    ],
    answer: "culex mosquito",
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "The malaria is spread in birds by__.",
    options: ["Anopheles", "Aedes", "culex", "Dengue"],
    answer: "Aedes",
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Biological method comprises of___steps.",
    options: ["5", "7", "6", "8"],
    answer: "6",
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "A litre of water weighs__.",
    options: ["1000g", "989g", "780g", "879g"],
    answer: "1000g",
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question:
      "Female mosquitoes need the blood of__for the maturations of their eggs.",
    options: ["Mammals", "Birds", "A and B", "Reptiles"],
    answer: "A and B",
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "The most basic step of biological method is__.",
    options: [
      "observations ",
      "experimentation",
      "Deductions",
      "hypotheses",
    ],
    answer: "experimentation",
  },
  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "Cinchona bark contains__.",
    options: ["quinine", "quina-quina", "basoquine", "resochine"],
    answer: "quinine",
  },
  {
    numb: 17,
    question: "The number of organisms on Earth is almost__.",
    options: ["Ten thousand", "Two lac", "20 lac", "one crore"],
    answer: "one crore",
  },
  {
    numb: 18,
    question: 'Plasmodium is the cause of malaria. This statement is a__.',
    options: ["hypotheses", "Deductions", "Theory", "Law"],
    answer: "Law",
  },
  {
    numb: 19,
    question: "Man always remained a__.",
    options: ["biologist", "chemist", "geologist", "scientist"],
    answer: "biologist",
  },
  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "Which of the followings is an effective drug for treating Malaria?",
    options: ["Disprein", "Actified", "quinine", "Theragram"],
    answer: "quinine",
  },
];
